freecrm.com 2010-06-21

# Free CRM Privacy Policy effective 06.13.2008

CRM ASP Inc. PRIVACY STATEMENT for www.FreeCRM.com (effective 06.13.2008) [](http://www.truste.org/ivalidate.php?url=www.freecrm.com&sealid=101)

1\. What personally identifiable information CRM ASP Inc. collects.  
2\. What personally identifiable information third parties collect through the Web site.  
3\. What organization collects the information.  
4\. How CRM ASP Inc. uses the information.  
5\. With whom CRM ASP Inc. may share user information.  
6\. What choices are available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of the information.  
7\. What types of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under CRM ASP Inc. control.  
8\. How users can correct any inaccuracies in the information.  

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should first contact CRM ASP Inc. by privacy@crmasp.com, PHONE, or POSTAL MAIL numbers listed below. 

TRUSTe Privacy Program

CRM ASP Inc. is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build user's trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the Web site www.FreeCRM.com. 

Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Customer Support at 866-829-7011. 

If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact TRUSTe at http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns. 

Information Collection and Use

Your data is 100% private -- we do not use the data that you put into the system for any purpose other than supporting your CRM system. The data that you put in shall be and always will remain the sole property and private data of those individuals and organizations that input the data into this system. This data is never shared with any outside organizations or 3rd parties. In the event that our company becomes acquired, insolvent, comes under new ownership or any other change in corporate structure, we shall always insure that your data is completely private and never becomes compromised. 

Information Collection

CRM ASP Inc. collects information from our users at several different points on our Web site. We also collect our client's information as entered by the client. We treat both types of information as confidential. 

Registration

In order to use Web site, a user must first complete the registration form. During registration a user may give[s] contact information (such as name and email address). We use this information to contact the user about services on our site for which he has expressed interest. For our free service where all information is optional, portions of the site may not function unless the user inputs specific information required by the site functions. 

Orders

We request information from the user on our order form for paid services. A user must provide contact information (such as name, email, and billing address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer's orders. If we have trouble processing an order, the information is used to contact the user. 

Information Use

Anonymous Profile

We store anonymous user information that we collect through cookies, log files, clear gifs, and/or third parties to create a profile of our users. A profile is anonymous stored information that we keep for reporting user information and demographics to our advertisers in a completely anonymous fashion, without any personally identifiable information. Our profiling is always s anonymous and is never tied to the users personally identifiable. This profile is used to provide anonymous user data and submitted, optional demographics to site advertisers. We do not share your personal information with other third parties. 

Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site, but is tied to a random number or string representing the current user session. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies that are never personally identifiable by clients. For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user's hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your browser help file directions. 

By setting a cookie on our site, users would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If users reject the cookie, they may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of our site. 

Some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies, once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. 

Third Party Advertising

The ads appearing on this Web site may be delivered to users by third parties or ourselves or any of our Web advertising partners. Information about users' visit to this site, such as number of times they have viewed an ad (but not user name, address, or other personal information), is used to serve ads to users on this site. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by CRM ASP Inc. only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. 

Log Files

Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

Blog and Live Chat

If you use the blog on this Web site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. 

We use live chat in order to better serve our users, when using live chat you will be asked to supply your name and email address so that our operators may better assist you.

Tell a Friend / Recommendations

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. CRM ASP does not store this information. 

We use live chat in order to better serve our users, when using live chat you will be asked to supply your name and email address so that our operators may better assist you.

Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)

We may employ or our third party advertising partners may employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. The main difference between the two is that clear gifs are invisible on the page and are much smaller, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. Clear gifs are not tied to users' personally identifiable information, except as noted for html emails. 

Clear Gifs can "work with" existing cookies on a computer if they are both from the same Web site or advertising company. That means, for example, that if a person visited "www.companyX.com", which uses an advertising company's clear gif, the Web site or advertising partner would match the clear gif's identifier and the advertising company's cookie ID number, to show the past online behavior for that computer. This collected information would then be given to the advertising company [or site. 

In addition, we may use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by the recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If users would like to opt-out of these emails, please see the Opt-out section. 

Communications from the Site

Special Offers and Updates: We may send new members a welcoming email to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections. 

Newsletter: If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections. 

Service Announcements

On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature. Users may opt-out of these communications. Please see our Choice and Opt-out section. 

Customer Service

We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account we reply via email or phone, in accordance with the user's wishes. 

Sharing

Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)

We share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personally identifiable information. 

Third Party Advertisers

CRM ASP Inc. does not share Web site usage information about users with third parties for the purpose of targeting our Internet banner advertisements on this site and other sites. For example, CRM ASP Inc. uses cookies and clear GIFs on this site, which allow them to recognize a user's cookie when a user visits this site. The information they collect and share through this technology is not personally identifiable and is not shared with third parties. 

These are the instances in which we will share users' personal information: 

We ONLY share personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order, legal process served on our Web site or as required by law. 

Third Party Intermediaries

We use an outside credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. These companies do not retain or share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. 

Service Providers

We may partner with other third parties to provide specific services. When the user signs up for these particular services, we may share names, or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. These third parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services. 

Business Transitions

In the event CRM ASP Inc. goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users' personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. Users will be notified via email or prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days for a change of ownership or control of their personal information. If as a result of the business transition, the users' personally identifiable information will be used in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection they will be given notice and/or choice consistent with our notification of changes section. 

Choice/Opt-out

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to unsubscribe in the subject line in the email or email us at unsubscribe@crmasp.com. Users may also click on any links contained within the email newsletters which will present a web page to opt-out of any particular newsletter. We also offer an opt-out mechanism on the member setup pages or the user may contact us at phone or postal mail to opt-out. 

Some communications from the system are required for all members; the only way to opt-out of system information messages is to terminate the active account as these are required system messages. Users wishing to terminate their accounts may do so at any time by emailing us at support@freecrm.com or requesting via telephone support during normal business hours. 

Users of our site are always notified when their information is being collected by any outside parties. We do this so our users can make an informed choice as to whether or not they should proceed with services that require an outside party. 

Links

This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, CRM ASP Inc., are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site. 

Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). 

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

Enhancement of Marketing Profile

We may purchase third party marketing data and add it to our existing user database (not specifically the client's information) to better target our advertising and provide pertinent offers we think our users would be interested in. We may use this information to enhance or overlay the 'profile' of individual users. This aggregate marketing data is therefore tied to the users' anonymous profile information. See also the "Profile." 

Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information

If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users' personally identifiable information. This can usually be done at the member setup and information page or by emailing our Customer Support or, contact us by telephone or postal mail. 

Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. 

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page. 

Contact Information If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: 

Tel: 866-829-7011 / 415-874-8040 Fax: 480-275-3595

Email [privacy@crmasp.com](mailto:privacy@crmasp.com)

Postal Address 58 West Portal Avenue #149 San Francisco, CA 94127
